<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<travelogue>
	<title>Madagascar</title>
	
	<section id="1">
		<title>Antananarivo</title>
		
		<note>Eleven hour flight from Paris. Arrival around midnight. The 
		airport is pretty crowded, even though no other flights have arrived or 
		are leaving. Taxi to the city, half an hour, empty streets. The hotel I 
		had called the week before to make a reservation is closed, or at least 
		I can't get anyone to let me in, despite some shouting and banging on 
		the door. After trying a few more places I am glad to finally get stay 
		at the hotel Raphia, which turns out to be an excellent choice 
		anyways.</note>

		<note>While Antananarivo doesn't have any major tourist attractions it 
		is an interesting place to wander around a bit, provided you don't mind 
		crowds, dust, holes in the sidewalk, beggars and chaotic traffic.</note>
		
		<note>The Tsimbazaza zoo and botanical garden outside the city is a 
		quiet and pleasant place to get a break after seeing the city.</note>
		
		<image id="4-01">The Zoma market area.</image>
		<image id="4-04">Typical traffic situation.</image>
		<image id="4-06">Better traffic situation.</image>
		<image id="1-03">Inside the Tsimbazaza garden.</image>
		<image id="1-02">The Rova, or queen's castle, or what's left of it.</image>
		<image id="4-10">One of the few street lights in the city.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="2">
		<title>Antananarivo to Antsirabe</title>
		
		<note>Taxi-brousse to Antsirabe. Taxi-brousse are private cars and 
		minibuses operating on a non-fixed schedule, and due to the lack of 
		alternatives the main form of transport. Arrival around lunch.</note>
		
		<note>Antsirabe used to be a classy colonial retreat, though nowadays 
		all I notice are the somewhat to many pousse-pousse, small 
		rickshaws. Lots of tourists, nearly all of them from Madagascar.</note>
		
		<image id="1-07">A pousse-pousse, from a safe distance.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="3">
		<title>Antsirabe to Fianarantsoa</title>
		
		<note>Breakfast at Helena's Salon de Thé which offers interesting 
		interpretations of concepts such as croissant and pain au 
		chocolat.</note>

		<note>Taxi-brousse to Fianarantsoa, beautiful trip. Arrival in the late 
		afternoon. Hôtel Moderne. Nice rooms, nice restaurant and helpful 
		staff.</note>
	</section>
	
	<section id="4">
		<title>Ranomafana</title>
		
		<note>Shaky two hour trip to Ranomafana National Park, back to 
		Fianarantsoa in the afternoon.</note>
		
		<image id="1-40">The road to Ranomafana.</image>
		<image id="1-08">Waterfall near the park entrance.</image>
		<image id="1-39">The river flowing through the park.</image>
		<image id="1-12">Path inside the park.</image>
		<image id="1-26">A family of small lemurs cuddled together.</image>
		<image id="1-37">Two bigger lemurs.</image>
		<image id="1-19">Twisted trees.</image>
		<image id="1-09">Yet another path.</image>
		<image id="1-28">View over the park.</image>
		<image id="1-24">Fern tree.</image>
		<image id="1-31">Green stuff...</image>
		<image id="1-32">...everywhere.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="5">
		<title>Fianarantsoa</title>
		
		<image id="2-02">View on the city from the west.</image>
		<image id="2-03">Some houses on the slope to the west of the city.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="6">
		<title>Fianarantsoa to Manakara</title>
		
		<note>After waiting a few hours for the last running passenger train in 
		the country to be fixed, I get on a taxi-brousse with some other 
		impatient travelers like me. Another three hours later we finally 
		leave.</note>

		<note>Beautiful but rough trip. We arrive in Manakara close to midnight.</note>
	</section>

	<section id="7">
		<title>Manakara</title>
		
		<note>Nice beach, though the ocean is a bit rough and the sharks 
		unfriendly.</note>
		
		<image id="2-07">View from the charming but decaying Hôtel de Manakara.</image>
		<image id="2-06">Path next to the beach.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="08">
		<title>Manakara to Mananjary</title>
		
		<note>Short flight with a great view on the Pangalanes, a semi-
		artificial system of canals parallel to the ocean extending from 
		Manakara all the way up to Toamasina.</note>
		
		<note>At midnight a once-in-seven-years one-month-long circumcision 
		ritual of a local tribe is opened. No special visual effects, 
		but an interesting atmosphere nevertheless.</note>
		
		<image id="2-25">Air Mad.</image>
		<image id="2-14">One of the villages along the way.</image>
		<image id="2-15"></image>
		<image id="2-19"></image>
		<image id="2-21"></image>
		<image id="2-26">Bungalows at the Hôtel Jardin de la Mer.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="9">
		<title>Mananjary</title>
		
		<note>The patron of the restaurant La Route des Epiciers is able to 
		organize a pirogue, a type of wooden boat widely used in this area, for 
		a day for some French people and myself. We paddle 12 kilometers to the 
		south, where the canal widens into a small lake. Picnic at the beach 
		between the lake and the ocean, then back home.</note>
		
		<note>Next morning I try to find a motor-pirogue to Nosy Varika. I soon 
		realize that few people here speak French. Finally I do find someone who 
		intends to leave this evening. Though later on he decides that his boat 
		is still too empty, so we won't leave until tomorrow morning.</note>
		
		<image id="2-29">One of the narrower parts of the canal.</image>
		<image id="2-31"/>
		<image id="2-35">A medium sized pirogue.</image>
		<image id="2-36">People doing laundry and fishing.</image>
		<image id="2-28"/>
		<image id="2-27">Sunset in Mananjary.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="11">
		<title>Mananjary to Nosy Varika</title>
		
		<note>Twelve hour journey abourd a two by ten meter motor-powered 
		pirogue, along with a dozen bags of salt, some chickens, people, 
		all kinds of baggage, mail and various other things.</note>
		
		<note>In Nosy Varika I'm pointed to the nearest (and only) hotel, La 
		Petite Oasis, which has a few simple bungalows.</note>
		
		<image id="2-39">One of the lakes on the way.</image>
		<image id="3-01">Sunset along the canal.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="12">
		<title>Nosy Varika</title>
		
		<note>Finding transport from Nosy Varika onward turns out to be 
		difficult. I decide to continue by foot, after resting a day.</note>
		
		<image id="3-03">The main road to Nosy Varika.</image>
		<image id="3-02">The only jeep I can find.</image>
		<image id="3-04">The beach a kilometer south of the village.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="13">
		<title>Nosy Varika to Mahanoro</title>
		
		<note>Eight hour, forty kilometer hike to Masomelka with a guide I 
		hired for the day. Get a ride with a delegation of the World Food 
		Program agency which happened to visit the village that day all the way 
		to Mahanoro by boat, jeep and ferry.</note>

		
		<image id="3-07">Leaving Nosy Varika.</image>
		<image id="3-08"></image>
		<image id="3-09"></image>
		<image id="3-10"></image>
		<image id="3-11">One of the dryier parts along the way.</image>
		<image id="3-13"></image>
		<image id="3-14"></image>
		<image id="3-15">A single zebu.</image>
		<image id="3-17"></image>
	</section>

	<section id="14">
		<title>Mahanoro to Toamasina</title>
		
		<note>The only taxi-brousse to Toamasina is broken, so I get on a pick-up 
		truck to the next bigger village to the north, Vatomandry. There we 
		barely manage to catch up with the last taxi-brousse to Toamasina. Five 
		more hours. Hôtel Generation.</note>
		
		<image id="3-18">The beach in Mahanoro.</image>
		<image id="3-21">A village along the way.</image>
		<image id="3-22">The street near Mahanoro.</image>
	</section>

	<section id="15">
		<title>Toamasina</title>
		
		<note>Toamasina is one of the nicer cities in Madagascar. Which doesn't 
		mean much, but nevertheless.</note>

		<note>The Musée Regional de l'Université de Toamasina has some 
		traditional tools and instruments on display.</note>

		<note>The zoo/botanical garden near Ivoloina just outside the city is 
		small but really nice. Lots of lemurs, both free and in cages.</note>
		
		<image id="3-23">Free lemur.</image>
		<image id="3-26">Caged lemurs.</image>
	</section>
	
	<section id="16">
		<title>Toamasina to Nosy Boraha</title>
		
		<note>Half hour flight to Nosy Boraha, also known as Île Sainte Marie.</note>

		<note>Hôtel Orchidées on Nosy Nato, a tiny island at the south tip of 
		Nosy Boraha. Nice bungalows.</note>
	</section>
	
	<section id="17">
		<title>Nosy Boraha</title>
		
		<note>I rent a mountain bike from the hotel Soanambo. The road turns out 
		to be pretty rough, and it takes me over six hours to cycle around half 
		the island, but it's really worth it.</note>

		<note>Next day I have a closer look at Nosy Nato. The island is so small 
		you can walk around it in two hours, but you can easily get lost in the 
		interior.</note>
		
		<note>On my last day on Nosy Boraha I go diving, competently organized 
		through Il Balemottero in Ambodifotatra.</note>
		
		<image id="3-29"></image>
		<image id="3-30"></image>
		<image id="3-31"></image>
		<image id="3-32"></image>
		<image id="3-34"></image>
		<image id="3-35"></image>
		<image id="3-37"></image>
		<image id="3-33"></image>
		<image id="3-38"></image>
	</section>
	
	<section id="20">
		<title>Nosy Boraha to Antananarivo</title>
		
		<note>Flight back to Antananarivo.</note>
		
		<image id="3-40">Dry area near Antananarivo.</image>
	</section>
	
	<section id="21">
		<title>Antananarivo</title>
		
		<note>The hotel Saka Manga organizes one day jeep tours around 
		Antananarivo. Visit to the village of Ambohidratrimo on one of the hills 
		surrounding the Antananarivo. There are several old tombs here which are 
		still being used for various ceremonies. For lunch we stop at a small 
		crocodile farm near Ivato. Guess what's for lunch. They also have a nice 
		zoo with all kinds of reptiles.</note>
		
		<note>In the evening I get back to the airport, my flight back home 
		leaves around midnight.</note>
		
		<image id="4-11">Ambohidratrimo.</image>
		<image id="4-22">Women doing laundry.</image>
		<image id="4-23"></image>
		<image id="4-13">A chameleon.</image>
		<image id="4-15">Crocodiles.</image>
		<image id="4-16">Leguans.</image>
		<image id="4-26"></image>
		<image id="4-25">Fields outside Anatananarivo.</image>
		<image id="4-29">Road to one of the villages surrounding the city.</image>
	</section>
	
</travelogue>
